Curriculum Vitae

Personal Profile:

An enthusiastic, confident and highly competent Electrical Engineer with extensive automotive knowledge and experience. A proven people and project leader who is well organised, resilient and motivated to succeed.

Simon Rix

Self-motivated, enthusiastic with a can-do positive attitude and proven ability to ensure the smooth running of multiple projects. Natural ability to problem solve, generate ideas and solutions whilst striving for cost efficiencies and process effectiveness.

Employment History:

Employer: McLaren Automotive, Surrey
Position Held: Senior EDS Engineer
Duration: 03/2016 – Present

Sample of Achievements:

- Solely responsible for EDS P11/P13 Series project including MY update releases and leadership of engineering issues.
- EDS lead for P16 project which includes leading project design team. Supporting design reviews and supplier visits.
- Recognized and spot awarded for closing out multiple PPS (practical problem solving) issues within project constraints.

Role Deliverables:

- Led the creation and delivery of McLaren P16 EDS implementation plans which included timing plans/invest to budget/EDS road map and liaising with internal and external suppliers.
- Led the analysis and selection of EDS Supplier from supplier RFQ to business sign off
- Wrote EDS Tech Spec, completed RAT, DVP and DFMEA requirements associated with the product development cycle.
- Led project review meetings, ensuring regular attendance / project scheduled maintained and key actions completed
- Continue to lead P13 project release for harness VA/VE
- Working cohesively with the Production and Service functions to deliver Electrical support training and Production harness protection program setup.
- Create program notes and associated reporting pathway for the purpose of part improvement.
- Managing both EDS & CAD people resource to budget, both off-shore and on-site.
- Support the Integrate of new harness design tool between PREEvision/Arcadia/CatiaV5
- Work with Mclaren specific systems to include SAP and Maxim trained including Product Liability.

Employer: Contechs Consulting - Placement with McLaren Automotive, Surrey

Position Held: EDS Engineer Duration: 04/2015 – 03/2016

Sample of Achievements:

- Appointed Electrical Function Group Lead EDS Engineer responsible for a Mule build program and successfully led the car build program from laboratory to production.
- Solely responsible for designing and building a single ADI harness that transcends all variants within our Mule program. Delivered on time, to plan without error.

Curriculum Vitae

Simon Rix

• Confidently liaising with Senior Managers, Project Engineers and multi-function teams to coordinate and deliver detailed and challenging requirements.

Role Deliverables:

- Delivering key projects through successfully engaging with wider technical Functions, contractors, suppliers and workshop staff to deliver project plan on time and to budget.
- Competently managing budget demands and constraints, procurement timings.
- Effectively working as Build Engineer when required and re-engineering drawings to meet requirements of defined technician groups.
- Producing schematics, wiring diagrams and instructions, all within McLaren's process structure.
- Documenting continuous improvement, lessons learned and sharing findings within the Electrical Function Group team.
- Competent use of internal McLaren systems and Enovia V5 Catia.
- Rapid understanding of complex McLaren design.

Employer: Group Lotus PLC

Position Held: EEI Product Engineering Supervisor

Duration: 02/2012 to 11/2014

Position Held: EEI Engineering Duration: 02/1990 to 02/2012

Sample of Achievements:

- Electrical project lead for business critical proto-type build of 20 units, worth £40million over 4 years. Whilst managing a team of 6 electrical staff, I led key interface with prestige O.E.M client. My role required adaptability from a design engineer, build engineer to fault finder specialist working in the UK and abroad.
- Sole electrical accountability for a High Voltage (HV) and Low Voltage (LV) project for project duration (1 year). Experiential 3 cylinder engine installation, including a hybrid system, in a third party in-donor vehicle. Involving CAD, high skill usage due to significant complexities which resulted in successful car start up and onward business demonstrator to future customers.
- Interim dual-role involvement with an electrical R&D product issue. Through fault finding, process mapping and demonstrating my adaptability between electrical and field service skills the solution was identified and fix instruction implemented to UK and international field workers. Resulting in international sales office remaining operational and diverting significant business cost impact.
- Prototype Powertrain projects ranging from complex vehicle installations, motorsport, dyno testing and intelligent gearbox systems to product packaging and component testing. Customer driven analysis presentation using MS Office.

Role Deliverables:

- EEI lead on specialist projects to include:
 - Multiple High Voltage hybrid vehicles
 - Multiple Specialist engine projects and installations
 - Whole build luxury car prototype builds
 - Single seated racing cars
- Supervising Electrical Support Team

Curriculum Vitae

Simon Rix

- · Coordinating electrical support with the demands and deadlines for ongoing client projects
- Creation of AutoCAD drawings and implementation of AutoCAD designs on a daily basis
- Interpreting, analysing and applying prototype car scaled drawing through to production
- · Conducting fault finding and diagnostic assessments on vehicle and EMS
- Experience of working off site and abroad on vehicle testing analysis
- Liaising with a diverse multi-national client base and realizing their requirements
- Working as an integral part of a multi-disciplinary project team
- CAN compliance application including use of CAN analyser
- Working to quality standards: QS9001 and 5S

Further Training and Education:

Key Professional Training Courses:

Course Title	Provider	Date	Qualification
CATIA V5 Electrical Design	Intrinsys	2015	Dassault Systemes
CATIA V5 Fundamentals	Spires Engineering	2014	Dassault Systemes
Authorised Persons (HEV)	Sterling Power Training Ltd	Annual	Pass
GCSE Spanish	Adult Education	2005	GCSE B
First Aid at Work	Norvic Training Provider	2012	Pass
Defibrillator Training	NHS Ambulance Service	Annual	Pass

Education:

Institution	Course/Qualification	Date	Achievement
Norwich City College	ONC Electrical/Electronic Qualification	1990 – 1994	BTEC National Certificate Level 3
East Anglian Group Industry Training	EITB Standard Training in: • Electrical/Electronic • Turning/Milling/Welding/ Bench Fitting/ Electronic/ Electrical/Fabrication	1990 – 1991	NVQ Level 2
Costessey High School	GCSE	1985 – 1990	9 GCSE's Obtained

Leisure Interests:

Experienced former Football Manager of 11 years, and recently retired player of 25 years who successfully managed First Team squads and an array of player characteristics. Leading dressing-room motivation, game tactics and team ethos of winning without compromising sportsmanship. All skills transferable into employment.

Sport, Cooking, travel and home technology projects.